?Are you ready, kids
准备好了吗，孩子们
:Kids
!Aye, aye, Captain
: 儿童
！是啊是啊，队长
.I can't hear you
.我听不到你说话
:[louder ]
!Aye, aye, Captain
：[大声]
！是啊是啊，队长
♪ ...Oh ♪
♪ ...噢 ♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
?under the sea ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
?在海底♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ Absorbent and yellow
.and porous is he ♪
♪ 吸水性和黄色
.他是多孔的♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ If nautical nonsense be
...something you wish ♪
♪ 如果航海方面的废话是
...你想要的东西♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ Then drop on the deck
.and flop like a fish ♪
♪ 然后落在甲板上
.然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ ?Ready
!SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 准备好了
！海绵宝宝♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ !海绵宝宝 ♪
[laughs heartily ]
[尽情地笑]
plays airy tune][Captioning sponsored by THE ]
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
演奏轻快的曲调][字幕由 THE 赞助]
美国教育部
[and NICKELODEON
[和尼克罗迪恩
--There it is
.Grandma's house
——就在这儿
.奶奶家
What wonders
?await me today
有什么奇怪的
？今天等我
?Fresh-baked cookies
?新鲜出炉的饼干
?Story time
?故事时间
A sweater with love
?in every stitch
一件充满爱的毛衣
？每一针
?Aw, what am I waiting for
？噢，我还在等什么
!Grandma, Grandma, Grandma
！奶奶，奶奶，奶奶
!SpongeBob
!海绵宝宝
!Hi, Grandma
！嗨，奶奶
.Come in and sit for a while
.进来坐一会儿
,Have a cookie
.SpongeBob
,吃一块饼干
.海绵宝宝
Grandma, you make
the best cookies
.in the deep blue sea
奶奶，你做的
最好的饼干
.在深蓝色的大海里
...Oh, yeah
...哦，是的
[munches ]
[咀嚼]
[gulps ]
[咽口水]
...Grandma's cookies
...奶奶的饼干
Now, who wants to
?lick the spoon
现在，谁愿意
?舔勺子
!Oh! Me, me, me
！哦！我，我，我
And then we drove...
all the way home
然后我们就开车...
一路回家
with all the windows down
.in the freezing cold
所有窗户都放下
.在严寒中
Tell me another story
.about when I was a baby
告诉我另一个故事
.关于我还是个婴儿的时候
[cuckoo clock chimes 3:00 ]
[布谷鸟钟鸣响3:00]
!?gasps] 3:00 ]
！？喘息] 3:00 ]
I'm going to be late
!for work
我要迟到了
！为了工作
.Hop in my car
.I'll drop you off
.跳上我的车
.我送你下车
!Thanks, Grandma
！谢谢奶奶
...SpongeBob
!you forgot your kissy-kissy
...海绵宝宝
！你忘记了你的亲吻
.I sure did
.我确实做到了
[kisses ]
[亲吻]
!Bye, Grandma
!Thanks for the ride
！再见，奶奶
！感谢您的搭车
.Thank you, Squidward
.谢谢你，章鱼哥
[others chuckling ]
[其他人窃笑]
...Oh, brother
……哦，兄弟
[whistling ]
[吹口哨]
?Isn't this great
？这不是很棒吗
Everybody's
.in a good mood today
每个人的
.今天心情好
I love bursting
.your bubble, SpongeBob
我爱爆了
.你的泡泡，海绵宝宝
,They're laughing atyou
.not with you
,他们在嘲笑你
.不和你在一起
Did I do
?something funny
我做了吗
？有趣的事情
.Your forehead
.你的额头
?My forehead is funny
？我的额头很有趣
!Hey, grandma's boy
！嘿，奶奶的儿子
!Kissy-kissy-kissy
！亲吻亲吻
[...all laughing ]
[……全都笑了]
!No! You're wrong
！不！你错了
...There
there's nothing wrong
...那里
没什么问题
with getting kisses
!from your grandma
与接吻
！来自你奶奶
No... especially if you're
!a big baby who wears diapers
不...尤其是如果你
！一个穿尿布的大婴儿
[all laugh ]
[全场大笑]
And, and sucks his thumb
并且，并且吮吸他的拇指
and plays with dolls
和玩娃娃
and, um, wears pajamas
with feet in them
而且，呃，穿着睡衣
有脚在里面
,and carries his, um, uh
...binky around, and, uh
，并带着他的，嗯，呃
...宾基周围，并且，呃
:OTHERS
!All right already
:其他
！已经好了
.Cheer up, SpongeBob
.海绵宝宝，加油
I know someone
.who still likes you
我认识一个人
.谁还喜欢你
?Really
?You do, Squidward
？真的吗
？你知道，章鱼哥
!Yeah... your grandma
！是啊...你的奶奶
[...all laughing ]
[……全都笑了]
[...laughter continues ]
[……笑声继续]
[...all laughing ]
[……全都笑了]
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
[all laughing ]
[全都笑了]
!...Stop it
！...停下来
I have been publicly humiliated
!for the last time
我曾被公开羞辱
！最后一次
[crying ]
[哭泣]
:PATRICK
I'm sorry that happened
.to you, SpongeBob
：帕特里克
我很抱歉发生了这样的事
.给你，海绵宝宝
.Me, too
。我也是
You're the most adult person
.I know
你是最成熟的人
.我知道
.Thanks, Patrick
.谢谢，帕特里克
.You know how grandmas are
.你知道奶奶是怎样的
.They love babies
.他们喜欢婴儿
You just can't act
.like a baby around her
你只是无法行动
.就像她身边的婴儿一样
.You're right, Patrick
.你是对的，帕特里克
?Have I ever not been right
？我有没有说错过
[sizzling ]
[热气腾腾]
[honking ]
[鸣喇叭]
[wolf-whistle ]
[狼哨]
,You're a man now
SpongeBob
,你现在是个男人了
海绵宝宝
and it's time you
.started acting like one
现在是你的时候了
.开始表现得像一个人
!Yeah
！是的
Oh... but I'm not sure
.I know how
哦...但我不确定
.我知道怎么做
Allow me
.to demonstrate
请允许我
.证明
,First
.puff out your chest
,首先
.挺起胸膛
".Now say "tax exemption
”.现在说“免税
!Tax exemption
!免税
Now you must acquire
.a taste for free-form jazz
现在你必须获得
.对自由爵士乐的品味
[trumpet plays fast jazz riff ]
[小号演奏快速爵士即兴重复段]
,Okay, SpongeBob
!you're ready
，好吧，海绵宝宝
！你准备好了
.This is it
.就是这样
What are you going
?to tell Grandma
你要去做什么
?告诉奶奶
.I'm a grownup
.我是个大人了
.No ifs, ands or buts about it
.没有如果、和或但是
A man's got to do
.what a man's got to do
一个男人必须做的事
.男人必须做什么
And then you get behind her
.and I'll push
然后你就到她身后
.我会推动
.Patrick, we didn't say that
.帕特里克，我们没这么说
.Oh, yeah, right
.哦，是的，对了
All we need now
我们现在需要的一切
is the icing
.on the maturity cake
是锦上添花
.在成熟蛋糕上
I've been growing
.these babies for years
我一直在成长
.这些婴儿多年来
:BOTH
...Sideburns
：两者
...鬓角
.Oh, hello, SpongeBob
.哦，你好，海绵宝宝
.What a nice surprise
.多么好的惊喜啊
Come here, give your granny
.her kissy-kissy
过来，给你奶奶
.她的亲吻
...Mmm
...嗯
[kisses ]
[亲吻]
,Sorry, Grandmother
.but the kissing has to stop
,对不起,奶奶
.但是接吻必须停止
.Tell her like it is, SpongeBob
.就这样告诉她吧，海绵宝宝
.No more baby stuff
.不再有婴儿用品
.He is right, Grandmother
.他是对的，祖母
,Kisses are for babies
.which I am no longer
,亲吻是给婴儿的
.我不再是
.I have grown up
.我已经长大了
.It is nature's way
.这是自然之道
.Oh... you are absolutely right
.哦...你说得完全正确
?I am
？我是
.I mean, of course I am
.我的意思是，我当然是
You will definitely
not be treated like a baby
你一定会
不被当作婴儿对待
.around here ever again
.再次来到这里
I am glad you see it
.my way, Grandmother
我很高兴你看到它
.我的方式，祖母
:GRANDMA
Well, I'm glad
.that's settled
:奶奶
嗯，我很高兴
.就这样解决了
But what am I
going to do
但我是什么
要做
with all these
?fresh-baked cookies
与所有这些
?新鲜出炉的饼干
[chuckles ]
.Sorry, Grandmother
[笑声]
.对不起，祖母
We adults don't partake
.in the consumption of sweets
我们大人不参加
.在甜食的消费中
...Right, Pat
...对了，帕特
?rick
？里克
,Keep 'em coming
!Granny
，让他们继续来
！奶奶
[slurping ]
[吸吮]
.So much for no more baby stuff
.关于婴儿用品就这么多了
And don't forget the
!cookie-eating hat
并且不要忘记
!吃饼干的帽子
[laughs ]
[笑]
[both laughing ]
[两人都笑了]
!Hey
！嘿
!That's my cookie-eating hat
！那是我的吃饼干帽子
Uh... I mean, it was
!when I was a baby
呃...我是说，那是
！当我还是个婴儿的时候
...Grr
...咕噜
.Well, look who's here
.好吧，看看谁在这里
It's my big old
.adult grandson
这是我的大老
.成年孙子
Grandmother, I need to have
a mature conversation
奶奶，我需要
成熟的谈话
.with Mr. Patrick
.与帕特里克先生
!Patrick
!?What are you doing
！帕特里克
！？你在做什么
!Cookies! Warm milk
！曲奇饼！温牛奶
!A bib
！围兜
Is that a kissy mark
?on your forehead
那是吻痕吗
？在你的额头上
!We are supposed to be adults
！我们应该是成年人了
.Uh-uh-uh
.呃-呃-呃
No roughhousing
.with a full tummy
不打闹
.肚子饱满
[laughing ]
[笑]
?Who's the baby
?谁是宝贝
,I'm the baby, I'm the baby
!I'm the baby
，我是宝贝，我是宝贝
！我是宝宝
[clears throat ]
[清嗓子]
!Being grownup is boring
！长大了很无聊
.I love being a baby
.我喜欢当婴儿
.Besides, I don't get jazz
.此外，我不懂爵士乐
.Oh, poor Patrick
.哦，可怜的帕特里克
.I almost feel sorry for you
.我几乎为你感到难过
Trapped in the awkward phase
.of diaper days
陷入尴尬阶段
.尿布日
Never to know
the rich rewards
.of being a grownup
永远不知道
丰富的奖励
.成为一个成年人
.Here's a fresh batch of cookies
.这是一批新鲜的饼干
!All right
！好的
[munching ]
[咀嚼]
?Rewards, huh
？奖励啊
...Well, yeah, there's
...嗯，是的，有
[munching ]
[咀嚼]
...Let's see, we, uh
...让我们看看，我们，呃
.we went over the jazz
.我们回顾了爵士乐
[munching ]
[咀嚼]
,Oh, Grandma
.I'm full
，哦，奶奶
.我吃饱了
.More cookies
.更多饼干
[...vacuum cleaner running ]
[...吸尘器正在运行]
[whistling ]
[吹口哨]
.It appears to be my lunch hour
.现在似乎是我的午餐时间
.Grownups have to eat, too
.大人也要吃饭
.I guess this will have to do
.我想这必须做
:GRANDMA
Oh, you don't want
.this baby food
:奶奶
哦，你不想
.这个婴儿食品
How about a big piece
?of steamed coral
来一大块怎么样
？蒸珊瑚
.Oh, yeah, uh... great
.哦，是的，呃...太棒了
[crunching ]
[咀嚼]
!Nutritious
！营养丰富
:GRANDMA
!Story time
:奶奶
！故事时间
,Oh, boy! Story time
!story time, story time
，哦，孩子！故事时间
！故事时间，故事时间
?Story time
?故事时间
,You'll enjoy this
.Patrick
,你会喜欢这个
.帕特里克
It's a wonderful story
.about a magical sea leprechaun
这是一个美妙的故事
.关于神奇的海妖精
Oh, SpongeBob, you wouldn't be
.interested in this babybook
噢，海绵宝宝，你不会的
.对这本婴儿书感兴趣
Here's the technical manual
.on Routine Active Maintenance
这是技术手册
.关于日常主动维护
.Oh, uh, great
.噢，呃，太棒了
.Yeah... fascinating
.是啊...令人着迷
No pictures, just the way
.I like it
没有图片，只是方法
.我喜欢它
[munching ]
[咀嚼]
[crunch ]
[紧缩]
!Ohh! My wittle finger
！哦！我的小手指
,Hold still
.hold still
,保持不动
.保持不动
[kisses ]
[亲吻]
?All better
？一切都好起来了
:PATRICK
...Sorta
：帕特里克
...有点
This finger hurts
.a little bit, too
这个手指好痛
.也有一点点
[Grandma kisses ]
[奶奶的吻]
How about I give you
?a present
我给你怎么样
?一份礼物
!Oh, boy, I hope it's cookies
！哦，天哪，我希望是饼干
!All right
！好的
!Another hat
！另一顶帽子
.No, Patrick, it's a sweater
.不，帕特里克，这是一件毛衣
?Huh
？哈
.With love in every stitch
.每一针都充满爱
...No
...不
Don't I get
,a present
?Grandma
我不明白吗
,一份礼物
？奶奶
.Oh, I almost forgot
.哦，我差点忘了
Here's some
.office supplies
这是一些
.办公用品
.I didn't wrap them
.我没有包裹它们
I knew
.you wouldn't mind
我知道
.你不会介意的
[clock chimes 3:00 ]
[时钟敲响3:00]
.Uh-oh, 3:00
.呃哦，3:00
.Time for adults to go to work
.成年人上班的时间
.Bye-bye, SpongeBob
.再见，海绵宝宝
I'll bet you would fancy
?a nap, huh, Patrick
我敢打赌你会喜欢
？小睡一下吧，帕特里克
[Patrick yawns ]
[帕特里克打哈欠]
:GRANDMA
,You're still here
?SpongeBob
:奶奶
,你还在这里
?海绵宝宝
.Uh... I don't have to leave yet
.呃...我还不用离开
.I... can be late for work
.我...上班可能会迟到
No, no, no. That wouldn't
.be the adult thing to do
不，不，不。那不会
.成为成年人该做的事
,All right, uh
.I guess I'll be going
,好吧,呃
.我想我会去
I've, uh, got a lot
of adult-type business
我，呃，有很多
成人型企业
,to take care of
...so, uh
, 照顾
……所以，呃
.I'll see you later
.稍后见
Okay. Thanks for
.stopping by, SpongeBob
好的。谢谢
.顺便拜访，海绵宝宝
.Yup, that is it
.是的，就是这样
.Here I go
.我来了
Come again if you
.get the chance
如果你再来一次
.得到机会
,Out into the cold
...grownup world
,进入寒冷
...成人的世界
.alone... without a sweater
.独自一人...不穿毛衣
.Toodle-oo
.I don't know when I'll be back
.我不知道什么时候才能回来
.I know how busy you are
.我知道你有多忙
.So, uh... that's it
.所以，呃...就是这样
.Shh... he's asleep
嘘……他睡着了
...So... long
...这么久
!I don't want to grow up
！我不想长大
!I want cookies
！我想要饼干
!And milky
！还有乳白色的
I want a sweater
!with love in the stitches
我想要一件毛衣
！充满爱意
!I want to wear didies
！我想穿迪迪
!I want to ride in my wagon
！我想乘坐我的马车
I want to cuddle-wuddle
!with Mr. Stuffykins
我想拥抱
!和Stuffykins先生一起
I want to rocky-rock
!on my seahorsey
我想要摇滚
！在我的海马上
And I want kissy-kissy
!on my boo-boo
我想要亲吻
！在我的嘘声上
[crying ]
[哭泣]
[...crying ]
[……哭]
[...continues ]
[...继续]
[...wailing ]
[...哀号]
[...continues ]
[...继续]
ratcheting ]
[...like lawn sprinkler
棘轮]
[...像草坪洒水器
!Take it easy, SpongeBob
！放轻松，海绵宝宝
...SpongeBob
...海绵宝宝
!SpongeBob
!海绵宝宝
[crying and panting ]
[哭泣和气喘吁吁]
You don't have to
be a baby
你不必
做个婴儿
to get
.Old Grandma's love
得到
.老奶奶的爱
[sniffles ]
[抽鼻子]
?I don't
？我不
.Of course not
.当然不是
No matter
how grownup you get
没关系
你长大了多少
you will always be
.my Little Baby Boo
你将永远是
.我的小宝贝布布
[kisses ]
[亲吻]
And remember, you can
kiss your Grandma
请记住，你可以
亲吻你的奶奶
.and still be an adult
.并且仍然是一个成年人
.Here you go
。干得好
.Thanks, Grandma
.谢谢，奶奶
[munching and sighing ]
[咀嚼和叹息]
,Uh, Grandma
could you not mention this
，呃，奶奶
你能别提这个吗
to the guys
?down at The Krusty Krab
给伙计们
?在蟹堡王
.No problem
。没问题
[squeak ]
[吱吱]
[Squidward snickers ]
[章鱼哥窃笑]
[...all laughing ]
[……全都笑了]
[SpongeBob shrieks ]
[海绵宝宝尖叫]
[panting ]
[气喘吁吁]
Patrick, look, I
[got my... [ gasps
帕特里克，看，我
[得到我的……[喘气
[laughs ]
[笑]
.I'm sorry, Patrick
.对不起，帕特里克
,It's just
...for a second I thought
,这只是
……有一瞬间我想
Hey, you got the same
!reef-blower as me
嘿嘿，你也有同样的情况
!像我一样吹礁者
[whirs loudly ]
[大声呼呼]
!Tag, you're it
！标签，就是你了
[laughs ]
[笑]
[loud whirring, both laughing ]
[大声呼呼，两人都笑了]
[laughs ]
[笑]
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[laughs ]
[笑]
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
...Patrick
...帕特里克
you made my house
!sparkly clean
你建造了我的房子
！干净得闪闪发光
!Sure did
！当然有
We haven't improved
.Squidward's day yet
我们还没有进步
.章鱼哥的日子还没到
!Let's do his house
！让我们一起做他的房子吧
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[creaking ]
[吱吱作响]
[laughs ]
[笑]
!My turn
！轮到我了
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
!?What's going on out here
！？这里发生了什么事
We're playing
.with our new reef-blowers
我们正在玩
.使用我们的新型吹礁机
?Playing with a reef-blower
?玩吹礁器
That is the most childish thing
!I've ever heard of
这是最幼稚的事
！我听说过
!But it's fun
！但是很有趣
Fun? How could playing
乐趣？怎么可以玩
with one of those oversized
?hair dryers possibly be fun
与那些超大的之一
？吹风机可能很有趣
:PATRICK
.Like this
：帕特里克
.像这样
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
!Chafed
！恼怒
...All right, that's
……好吧，就是这样
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
,Let's do your house
.Patrick
,让我们来做你的房子吧
.帕特里克
!Yeah
！是的
?Huh
？哈
[panting, sizzling ]
[气喘吁吁，嘶嘶作响]
:SPONGEBOB
,Squidward
!you're steaming
:海绵宝宝
,章鱼哥
！你热气腾腾
You're like a steamed
.vegetable, only smarter
你就像蒸的一样
.蔬菜，只是更聪明
!Put my windows back
！把我的窗户放回去
,No problem
.Squidward
,没问题
.章鱼哥
We're on
.your side
我们在
.你的身边
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
...Any second now
...现在随时
...SpongeBob
...海绵宝宝
this is
.the final straw
这是
.最后一根稻草
I am going to move
so far away
我要搬家了
这么远
that I will be able
.to brag about it
我将能够
.吹嘘它
...I would
[clunk ]
...我会
[沉闷]
I would rather
tear out my brain stem
我宁愿
撕掉我的脑干
carry it
into the middle
携带它
到中间
of the nearest
four-way intersection
最近的
四路交叉口
and skip rope with it
并用它跳绳
than go on living
.where I do now
比继续生活
.我现在在哪里
.Hi there
。你好呀
?Is this the final straw
？这是最后一根稻草
Do you want to move so far away
?that you can brag about it
你想搬那么远吗
？你可以吹嘘它
Would you rather
tear out your brain stem
你愿意吗
撕掉你的脑干
walk out into the middle
...of the nearest three-way
走到中间
...最近的三路
...Four-way
...四路
Four-wayintersection
四向交叉路口
and skip rope with it
并用它跳绳
than continue living
?where you do now
比继续生活
?你现在在哪里
...Then move to
[static ]
...然后移动到
[静态]
.I hate this channel
.我讨厌这个频道
!No, no
！不，不
.Tentacle Acres...
.触手英亩...
Where happiness is
.just a suction cup away
幸福在哪里
.仅一个吸盘的距离
[pop ]
[流行音乐 ]
?Hello
？你好
?Yes, can I help you
？是的，我可以帮你吗
.I'm here about the happiness
.我是为了幸福而来的
.I'll be moving in now
.我现在就搬进去
?Are you alone
？你一个人吗
,No... I mean, yes
.there's nobody with me, yes
，不...我的意思是，是的
.没有人和我在一起，是的
.Peace and quiet
.和平与安静
Are you now or have you
?ever been a sponge
你现在还是有你
？曾经是一块海绵
.No
。不
...What about a
...怎么样？
.No, no starfish
.不，没有海星
,Just a regular, normal
...peace-loving
,只是一个普通的、正常的
...爱好和平
[loud rumbling ]
[隆隆声]
[doors creaking ]
[门吱吱作响]
[kids laughing ]
[孩子们笑]
...Heaven at last
……终于到了天堂
:BOTH
!Ohh
：两者
！哦哦
I've seen
more alert people
我见过
人们更加警觉
!in a retirement home
！在养老院
Oh, which way to
the Living Without
?a Brain seminar
哦，走哪条路
没有生活
?大脑研讨会
!Don't be late
！别迟到了
I've heard
better comebacks
我听说过
更好的回归
from a turkey
!sandwich
来自火鸡
!三明治
!Get a life
！获得生活
This place is better
!than I expected
这个地方更好
！比我预期的要好
.302... 303... and 304
.302...303...和304
!Beautiful
！美丽的
.And not a pineapple in sight
.看不到菠萝
.Good night, Clary
.晚安，克拉丽
.Tomorrow we begin life anew
.明天我们重新开始生活
[phone ringing ]
[电话铃声]
,304 New Life Street
.Squidward speaking
,新生街304号
.章鱼哥说话
[SpongeBob babbling ]
[海绵宝宝胡言乱语]
There is no way I am moving
!back there, SpongeBob
我无法移动
！回到那边，海绵宝宝
.I am finally among my own kind
.我终于属于自己的同类了
[SpongeBob babbling ]
[海绵宝宝胡言乱语]
!Now good-bye
！现在再见
[babbling ]
[胡言乱语]
[rooster crows ]
[公鸡打鸣]
[inhales deeply ]
[深吸一口气]
...Ahh
...啊啊
.I think I'll take my bike today
.我想我今天会骑自行车
[...creaking ]
[...吱吱作响]
.I'm my own man
.我是我自己的人
[clunk ]
[沉闷]
Now, these neighbors
.know how to live
现在，这些邻居
.知道如何生活
!...Intensive
！...密集的
...Hmm... I bet they won't have
...嗯...我打赌他们不会
[gasps ]
!Wow! They have it
[喘气]
！哇！他们有它
!Canned bread
！罐头面包
!This town is great
！这个小镇很棒
I would really be
...impressed if it had
我真的会
...印象深刻，如果它有
!an interpretive dance academy
！诠释性舞蹈学院
[...music playing ]
[...音乐播放]
Yeah... it's even better
!in a group
是啊……这样更好
！在一个组中
!This town is perfect
！这个小镇太完美了
[...clarinets playing ]
[...单簧管演奏]
!?A clarinet trio
!?单簧管三重奏
[...all playing ]
[...都在玩]
[rooster crows ]
[公鸡打鸣]
[inhales deeply ]
[深吸一口气]
!Ahh... another great day
！啊...又是美好的一天
.Oh, look
.哦，看
.Everybody's on their bike today
.今天每个人都骑自行车
.It just gets better and better
.它只会变得越来越好
.All together
.全部在一起
[all playing ]
[全部播放]
I sort of... don't feel
.like playing my clarinet today
我有点……没感觉
.就像今天演奏我的单簧管一样
.Yup, this is great
是的，这太棒了
They might as well rename
.this town Squidward's Paradise
他们不妨重新命名
.这个小镇是章鱼哥的天堂
.Or perhaps... Too Much Paradise
.或者也许...太多的天堂
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
?SpongeBob
?海绵宝宝
...Feh
...菲赫
[...whirring ]
[...呼呼]
[laughs ]
[笑]
[whistling ]
[吹口哨]
.Oops
.哎呀
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
!Ohh
！哦哦
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
[grunts ]
[咕哝]
[chuckles ]
[笑声]
[clears throat ]
[清嗓子]
.Leaves
。树叶
.Just getting the leaves
.刚拿到叶子
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[chuckles ]
[笑声]
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[laughing ]
[笑]
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[laughs ]
[笑]
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
!Oof
！钱币
[laughs ]
[笑]
Could you pipe down
?over there, Iron Lung
你能管下来吗
？那边，铁肺
[both laugh ]
[两人都笑了]
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[laughs ]
[笑]
Looks like when it comes
to having fun
看来来的时候
玩得开心
you don't have
.a leg to stand on
你没有
.一条可以站立的腿
[laughing ]
[笑]
!Hey, that's not funny
！嘿，这不好笑
!Yeah
！是的
What's going on
?over here
发生了什么事
？在这里
.It's that guy
.就是那个家伙
He's playing
.with a reef-blower
他在玩
.用吹礁机
?Playing? With a reef-blower
？玩？用吹礁机
That's the most childish thing
.I've ever heard of
这是最幼稚的事情
.我听说过
.But it's fun
.不过很有趣
[laughs ]
[笑]
How could you
possibly have fun
你怎么可以
可能玩得开心
with one of those
?oversized hair dryers
与其中之一
!Like this
！像这样
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[clarinet tooting ]
[单簧管鸣响]
!Ahh! Give it back! Please
！啊！把它还给我！请
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[laughing ]
[笑]
!Tag, you're it
！标签，就是你了
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
!...Whoa
！...哇哦
[laughing ]
[笑]
?What can I get you boys
？我可以给你们买点什么
[...whirring ]
[...呼呼]
[...laughing ]
[...笑]
What are you
?looking at
你是什么
？看着
.Those
。那些
:SPONGEBOB
.Here it is, Patrick
:海绵宝宝
.这是，帕特里克
Now we've just got to convince
.Squidward to come back home
.章鱼哥回家
?You got our apology cake
？你收到了我们的道歉蛋糕
!We're ready
！我们准备好了
!Yay
！耶
?Hello, can I help you
?您好，有什么可以帮到您吗
Can I get
a large number
?one, extra size
我可以得到吗
大量
?一、加大码
But you just ate three orders
.of fried oyster skins
但你才吃了三单
.炸蚝皮
...I love
.fried oyster skins
...我爱
.炸蚝皮
We're sorry, but your kind
.isn't allowed here
我们很抱歉，但你很友善
.这里不允许
,He's not leaving
.Orville
,他不会离开
.奥维尔
You got your
?nightstick ready
你得到了你的
?警棍准备好
[sniffs ]
[嗅嗅]
!?Fried oyster skins
...Oh
!?炸蚝皮
...哦
[buzz ]
[嗡嗡声]
[doors creak ]
[门吱吱作响]
I guess we got to
.order inside
我想我们必须
.里面订购
[yelling ]
[大喊]
[laughing ]
[笑]
[whirring ]
[呼呼]
[laughing ]
[笑]
[crowd yelling ]
[人群喊叫]
[laughing ]
[笑]
Hey! That looked
!like Squidward
嘿！那看起来
！像章鱼哥一样
[yelling ]
[大喊]
That looked
like Squidward also
那看起来
也喜欢章鱼哥
.in angry mob form
.以愤怒的暴徒形式
,Hold it right there
!Mr. Tentacles
, 就在那儿握住
！先生。触手
!Stay back
!I got gardening tools
！退后一步
！我有园艺工具
,Here
!just read this
,这里
!只需阅读此内容
?What is it
?这是什么
A well thought-out and
.organized list of complaints
一个经过深思熟虑和
.整理的投诉清单
[crowd yelling ]
[人群喊叫]
,Patrick, look
!it's Squidward
帕特里克，看
！这是章鱼哥
!Squidward
!We finally found you
！章鱼哥
！我们终于找到你了
!Get off me
！从我身上下来
.I'm not Squidward
.我不是章鱼哥
Are you
?Squidward now
你是吗
?现在的章鱼哥
!?Grievances
！？委屈
!This town is a grievance
！这个小镇是个冤屈
There should be a law
应该有法律
against so many stuck-up
!tightwads living in one place
反对这么多自以为是的人
！住在一处的吝啬鬼
This city needs
!to be destroyed
这座城市需要
！被摧毁
Or at least painted
.a different color
或者至少画了
.不同的颜色
F.Y.I., you don't
,have to live here
.you know
仅供参考，你没有
,必须住在这里
.你知道
!Hey, you're right
！嘿，你说得对
.And I'm leaving A.S.A.P
.我要尽快离开
?Are you Squidward
?你是章鱼哥吗
.No
。不
?Are you Squidward
?你是章鱼哥吗
.No
。不
?Are you Squidward
?你是章鱼哥吗
,That's okay
.take your time
,没关系
.慢慢来
Any one
of these Squidwards
任何一个
这些章鱼哥
could be the real
.Squidward, Patrick
可能是真实的
.帕特里克·章鱼哥
[boom ]
[繁荣]
[whooshing ]
[呼啸]
!Whoa-ho, freedom
！哇哦，自由
!Whoo-hoo
！呼呼
[Squidward laughing ]
[章鱼哥大笑]
...Well, we know one thing
...好吧，我们知道一件事
.It sure isn't that guy
.这肯定不是那个人
!Whoo-hoo-ee
！呼呼
Captioning sponsored by THE]
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
字幕由 THE 赞助]
美国教育部
[and NICKELODEON
[和尼克罗迪恩
Captioned byThe Caption Center]
[WGBH Educational Foundation
字幕由字幕中心提供]
[WGBH 教育基金会